Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/e-siva (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Java

Servlets

Spring Framework

Languages

Hindi

Telugu

English

Certifications

Registered Member & Candidate for an H1B Visa

Siva Kumar Edupuganti

Goldman Sachs | Full Stack Developer | Software Engineer Singapore

Summary

Experience: Full Stack Developer with 8 Years experience in IT Industry, Spring Expert and Database Expert, Microservices, Docker, Kubernetes, Development of Frameworks, Sound experience in software lifecycle.

5 Years experience of working on Cloud systems, Distributed Systems specialist, Core JAVA, J2EE, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring JDBC, JavaScript, jQuery.

A Strong coder; regardless of language and can write clean and effective code.

Specialties: Programming, Good knowledge on Algorithms, Data Structure, Enterprise Application Development and Enterprise Systems Integration, Full Stack Development.

Technologies known: J2EE, Servlets, JSP, Spring Framework, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Spring JDBC, JavaScript, jQuery

Interests: Algorithms, Java, Spring Framework, SQL/NoSQL Databases, Distributed Databases (Cassandra).

contact: sivaiitroracle9@gmail.com

Experience

Goldman Sachs
Senior Software Engineer
June 2018 - Present (2 years 10 months)
Singapore

- -- Working on Cash Equities Booking and Matching System
- -- Fully event driven and micro-services architecture
- -- Low latency distributed Systems

- -- Domain Driven Design
- -- Enterprise Systems Integration

Works Applications Co., Ltd.
Software Engineer
October 2016 - June 2018 (1 year 9 months)
Singapore

- * Backend/Platform Engineer (Cassandra, Kafka, Postgres)
- * Full Stack Web Development using J2EE, Spring Framework, SQL DBs, Cassandra and Javascript.
- * Java / J2EE & Spring Expert
- * Redis Cache, Kafka, Cassandra, Spark Enthusiast
- * NGinx, Tomcat
- * Microservices, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible
- * Distributed Systems

Living Analytics Research Centre (LARC)
Software Engineer - Research
August 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Worked on a Crowd Sourcing project which delivers Courier Services by delivering the packages from Warehouse across the island. Designed and implemented the recommendation engine, which recommends the assignments to the crowd workers so that they can be delivered with minimal detour (similar to Multi-Agent Orienteering problem). Also, developed a visualizer based on Java Swing and OpenStreetMap data to visualize and monitor the real-time worker movement.

SurePark
Internship / Part Time
May 2015 - August 2015 (4 months)
Singapore

Worked on Integrating the Hardware and Software of the Parking Sensors (IoT) Application. Worked on Amazon Web Services - Kinesis, MongoDB, NodeJS, JAVA.

ViSenze - Pioneering Visual Search & Image Recognition Software Engineer Internship February 2015 - April 2015 (3 months)

Worked on a software engineering intern on building of an automated tool to test the ViSenze.com website APIs. This data driven testing tool is developed on JAVA and TestNG Framework.

Oracle

Applications Engineer
June 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 7 months)

As a Software Developer at Oracle-GRC(Governace Risk and Compliance) team, worked on various functionalities of the EGRCM & EGRCC products. Mainly worked with JAVA, J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Oracle DB.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.)

National University of Singapore Master's Degree, Computer Science